nitrocloud.com 2014-07-18

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

Revised: 25 September 2013

At Nitro Software, Inc we are committed to ensuring the privacy of your personal information. We understand that privacy of your personal information is important. Our Privacy Policy tells you how we collect, use, distribute and protect personal information.

##### Validate TRUSTe privacy certification

Nitro Software, Inc has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe here. This Privacy Policy governs all sites that link to this policy.

Nitro Software, Inc complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Nitro has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Nitro's certification, please visit www.export.gov/safeharbor/

##### Information we collect

The types of information we collect and handle normally comprises:

Identity and contact details such as name, email address, phone number, credit card information, and mailing address

##### Product and service preferences

Normally, we collect your personal information from you but on occasions we may obtain information about you from others. We may collect additional information about your company to provide better service for volume orders.

We only collect information which is necessary for the purposes of your dealings with us. We do not collect information about anyone's political or religious beliefs, ethnic background, criminal history or sexual preferences. 

##### Purpose of collection & use of personal information

The purpose for which we collect this information is to assist us in providing you with the products and services you have requested. We will not use your personal information for any purpose which is not related to the products or services you have requested or for any purpose which you would not reasonably expect us to use the information. We typically use your information for the following purposes:

##### Registration

We request certain personally identifiable information from you on the registration form and to enable you to create a user name and password when applicable. We use this information to contact you about the services on our site in which you have expressed interest.

##### Orders

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

##### Bulletin boards/chat rooms/blogs/forums

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

##### Customer testimonials/comments/reviews

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you would like to have us remove any of your comments, please contact us.

#### Communications from the site

##### Special offers and updates

We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special offers, and promotions. You can sign up for these emails from various pages on our sites. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out.”

##### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section.

##### Product/service-related announcements

We will send you strictly product/service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, to assist you with product usage or notification of product and service maintenance, we might send you an email.  
Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you can contact us.

##### Customer Service

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify information you provided. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.

##### Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [unsubscribe@nitropdf.com.](mailto:unsubscribe@nitropdf.com)

##### Sharing and disclosure

We will share or sell your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties except as described in this privacy policy (see "Business Transitions")

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. We will not disclose information about you to anyone else unless the disclosure:

is required by law; or

is authorized by law (for example to protect our interest or where we have a duty to the public to disclose that information); or

has been consented to by you.

##### Business Transitions

In the event Nitro Software, Inc goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email or prominent notice on our Web site for 30 day of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

##### Access

You may request that we provide you with access to the personal information we hold about you at any time. We will respond to your request for access within 30 days. If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, delete/remove or deactivate it by making the change in your account or by emailing us or by contacting us by postal mail at the contact information listed below. Generally we will be able to provide you with such access. However, where:  
the access impacts on the privacy of others;

the request for access is frivolous or vexatious;

there are existing or anticipated legal proceedings

such access can be denied under law or by law enforcement agency; or

where the information is evaluative.

We may not be able to provide you with access to such information. If we deny your request for access, we will let you know why. We may also charge a fee to cover our reasonable costs associated with your request.

##### Personal information security and data retention

We will take all reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. This includes both physical and technological security measures. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100%% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

##### Website

We only collect personal information from our website if you submit details to us via email or forms on our website. The information collected is limited to your email address and the contents of any message you may send to us. Personal information collected from our website will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided it and it will not be added to a mailing list or used for any other purpose without your consent. Our website uses various types of cookies and other tracking technologies:

Per-session cookies: Used to assess and improve the performance of the web site for our users. These cookies are anonymous and in no way identify users.

Persistent cookies: Used to make areas of the site that require a person to be logged in easier to use. For example, managing Expert Support enquiries.

Third Party Cookies: The use of cookies by third parties such as our tracking utility company and service providers are not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information 

Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs) 

We and our third party advertising partner employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here: http://preferences.truste.com/. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

##### Links to other sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Nitro Please be aware that we, Nitro, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

##### Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. 

This Privacy Policy was last amended June 10, 2013.

##### Contact us

If you require more detailed information about our information handling practices or if you have any concerns about our handling of your personal information, please let us know by going to the Contact Us webpage on this site.

Nitro Software, Inc   
225 Bush Street, Suite 700   
San Francisco, CA 94104
